IPs & ASNs
----------

We distribute Internet number resources to our members and provide tools to help them manage their allocations and assignments.

------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Analyse
-------

We collect a wide range of Internet data and provide statistics and tools you can use for your own operations and analyses.

------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Community
---------

More information about RIPE

------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Membership
----------

Get information about your membership, the benefits you get and how you can participate and shape RIPE NCC's activities.

----------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Events
------

The RIPE community carries out much of its work through mailing lists, but face-to-face meetings are equally important.

-------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------------------------

-------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Support
-------

We support members and the RIPE community through several channels to offer timely and efficient help – whether it’s a ticket, a tweet or a training course.

---------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

------------------------------------------------------------

Close

Publications
------------

Stay informed about everything Internet-related, from RIPE Policy and RIPE NCC member information to RIPE Labs blog posts and the latest Internet news.

-----------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------

Close

About
-----

We're a not-for-profit membership association, a Regional Internet Registry and the secretariat for the RIPE community supporting the Internet.

-------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

-----------------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------

Close

* [ ] 
    
    Search
    
     Search
    
    Your IP Address is: [51.195.149.220](https://apps.db.ripe.net/db-web-ui/query?searchtext=51.195.149.220)
    
    Tip: try using "quotes around your search phrase"
    
* Apps

* Menu
    
    Close
    
    Apps

* [ ] 

[Home](https://www.ripe.net/) / [About](https://www.ripe.net/about-us/) / [Legal](https://www.ripe.net/about-us/legal/) / [RIPE NCC Privacy Statement](https://www.ripe.net/about-us/legal/ripe-ncc-privacy-statement/)

RIPE NCC Privacy Statement
==========================

This is a live document. We will keep reviewing our processes and updating the Privacy Statement accordingly.

1\. Introduction
----------------

The RIPE NCC respects the privacy of your personal information and is committed to protecting the personal information that you provide. This RIPE NCC Privacy Statement applies to all personal information the RIPE NCC processes, including the collecting, publication, sharing and usage of personal information. The RIPE NCC Privacy Statement describes how the RIPE NCC processes your personal data and how you can access and make changes to your personal data.

2\. Processing your personal data
---------------------------------

The main purpose for which the RIPE NCC processes personal information is to support its role as a Regional Internet Registry (RIR). The main activity to fulfil this role is the registration and administration of Internet number resources, including the maintenance of the public RIPE Database (see 2.1).

Additionally, the RIPE NCC processes personal information for the purpose of performing activities for the benefit of the RIPE NCC members or for the benefit of the RIPE community (see 2.2).

### 2.1. Personal data in the RIPE Database

The public RIPE Database shows registration details of Internet number resources. The records may contain contact details (name, email address, phone and fax numbers and postal address) of persons responsible for the operation of networks or routers and/or for maintaining the information in the RIPE Database. The records may also contain geolocation information (e.g. country code, region, etc) of where registered Internet number resources are used.

In some cases, the RIPE NCC provides the initial registration. Subsequently, the personal information (e.g. contact details, geolocation information) pertaining to a specific registration is provided and maintained by a person authorised by, or acting on behalf of, the person or entity to which the Internet number resources have been registered. Updating is subject to an authentication and authorisation procedure (see 5). Please note that the RIPE NCC is not responsible for data entered into the RIPE Database by third parties. The person who enters personal data is responsible for keeping all data they maintain accurate and up-to-date, including maintaining correct contact details and receiving the relevant individual’s consent for publishing their personal data in the RIPE Database (see 5).

The RIPE NCC publishes the contact details as part of the registration details of Internet number resources to make it possible for the RIPE NCC and the Internet network community to contact the appropriate persons when it is necessary:

* To secure the proper functioning of the Internet;
* To prevent or redress possible misuse of the Internet;
* To improve the quality of the data;
* To protect the information stored in the RIPE Database;
* To prevent any unauthorised modification of information stored in the RIPE Database;
* To ensure accountability for information entered into the RIPE Database.

The RIPE Database may also be mirrored to databases operated by other RIRs, excluding database objects that are meant to include personal information. The databases of other RIRs may also be mirrored to databases operated by the RIPE NCC. This system allows users to retrieve data on all Internet resource registrations worldwide from the RIR in their region  
  
The RIPE NCC also, for the purposes specified above, allows proxy access to the RIPE Database via third parties. In addition, third parties may use a Near Real Time Mirror (NRTM) of the RIPE Database or access its contents in bulk via nightly dump and split files that are published by the RIPE NCC. In both cases, database objects that are meant to include personal information are excluded.

Where necessary for the above purposes, and to comply with statutory obligations, the RIPE NCC may also keep historical data (data that was published in the RIPE Database before the record was updated) and RIPE Database update requests.

### 2.2. Processing your personal data for other purposes

In addition to the collection and use of personal data in relation to the RIPE Database, the RIPE NCC provides other services and activities that may require the processing of your personal information. These include:

1. RIPE NCC member services: the RIPE NCC may request contact details for services such as relationship management, accounting and billing;
2. LIR Portal and the RIPE NCC website (www.ripe.net): processing of messages, service requests and information requests;
3. RIPE community and RIPE NCC membership mailing lists: messages including name, email address, date and message content are published in the mailing lists and mailing list archives to support the open and transparent RIPE Policy Development Process and discussions of membership-related issues;
4. Event registration administration for meetings, training courses and other organised events: the RIPE NCC may publish lists of attendees on a website as part of its commitment to open and transparent policy development. These lists contain the name of the attendee and their organisation, but no contact details or other personal details.
5. Publicly-available services as defined in the RIPE NCC Website and Publicly Available Services Terms of Service: the RIPE NCC may request contact details for purposes related to the provision and proper function of these services such as information requests, installation, support, maintenance, billing, relationship management and administration.

The RIPE NCC may use contact details provided in relation to all of the above activities to send you relevant information on its activities and services, such as announcements on network upgrades, outages, RIPE NCC services, RIPE Meetings, training courses and other organised events. The RIPE NCC may also forward public messages to a particular mailing list on occasion if it is relevant and appropriate for that list. If you do not wish to receive such messages, you can unsubscribe yourself at any time (see 5).

In addition to the above, the RIPE NCC may register, process or transfer your personal data where such is required pursuant to a statutory duty.

### 2.3. Sharing your personal data with third parties

The RIPE NCC may engage third parties for the provision of RIPE NCC services. In such cases, personal data collected for that particular purpose may be shared with these parties.

The RIPE NCC undertakes to engage parties that offer equivalent levels of security and protection and to make any appropriate contractual and organisational arrangements so that the data shared is limited to that required for the respective purpose and is not processed for longer than necessary.

If for the provision of the third-party services,  personal data is transferred to a country outside the European Economic Area, this will happen in accordance with the Dutch and EU data protection laws.

3\. Protection and secrecy of your information
----------------------------------------------

The RIPE NCC maintains strict procedures to authenticate people's identity and verify their right to authorise changes to their personal information.

Personal data held in the RIPE Database is available to the public. Use of the RIPE Database is subject to the [RIPE Database Terms and Conditions](https://www.ripe.net/manage-ips-and-asns/db/support/documentation/terms/). The RIPE NCC operates a technical query-limiting process as well as an [Acceptable Use Policy](https://www.ripe.net/manage-ips-and-asns/db/support/documentation/ripe-database-acceptable-use-policy/) to prevent data mining of large amounts of personal data through the RIPE Database query service. People attempting to abuse this service will have their access to the RIPE Database blocked.

The RIPE NCC maintains a high level of physical security and protection for all of its computer and network facilities, especially those in which personal information may be stored.

4\. Use of Cookies
------------------

#### 4.1 What is a cookie and what are cookies used for?

“Cookies” are small files that a browser can record after visiting a website. These files are set on your computer (or any other device with which you visit a website) through your browser.

The RIPE NCC is using cookies. By indicating your choice and allowing only the required cookies or accepting them all, you confirm that you are aware of the cookies the RIPE NCC is using, and the purposes these cookies are used for, as described herein.

Websites operated by the RIPE NCC may use cookies that:

* Are strictly necessary for the provision of the services that are available through the website and facilitate your use of these services (e.g. to identify you when you are logged in)
* Improve your experience by recording information about your settings (e.g. your location)
* Collect anonymous statistical information on the use of the website that help us improve the performance of the RIPE NCC website (e.g. the number of visitors to each part of our websites and their origin)
* Help us study the IPv6 capability of visitors, by making sure that your IPv6 capability is only measured once

The RIPE NCC **does not use** cookies for online behavioural advertising purposes nor does it share information collected via cookies with any third parties.

Some of the cookies described above are deleted once you close your browser. Others are set for longer periods of time.

On websites operated by the RIPE NCC where no cookies are set or only strictly necessary cookies are present, visitor consent is not required. In these cases, there may be no cookie banner.

For detailed information about the cookies used by the RIPE NCC, the purpose of these cookies and the period they remain active, please see [the list of cookies](https://www.ripe.net/about-us/legal/cookies/).

#### 4.2 Third party cookies

During your visit to the RIPE NCC website, third parties may also set cookies on your device. These cookies are set if you choose to view third-party content embedded on our website, such as a YouTube video, and are beyond the control of the RIPE NCC.  
  
Prior to viewing third-party content on our website, the RIPE NCC will inform you that by viewing such content, the third-party may set cookies and process your personal data. It will also record your permission to view that party’s content on our website once or for a longer period. If you do not agree to either of these options, the third-party content will not be displayed on our website.

#### 4.3 Disabling cookies

You can disable cookies by adjusting your browser settings Please check the “help” menu of your browser for information about how to change your cookie preferences. However you may not be able to use all website features if cookies are disabled.

5\. Accessing and changing your information
-------------------------------------------

You have the right to ask that inaccurate or incomplete data relating to you is rectified. In order to fulfil our obligation, the RIPE NCC will ask you to identify yourself.

RIPE NCC members can view their registration information online via the LIR Portal. You may be able to access and change your personal data using the LIR Portal on behalf of your organisation. The RIPE NCC will help those who may have trouble modifying their own data. To prevent unauthorised access and changes to your personal data, you will have to log in with your credentials (i.e. Reg ID, username and password).

If you are not authorised to change your personal data in the RIPE Database, please refer to the authorised person (the maintainer, i.e. the person or entity indicated on the record as “mnt-by:”). The maintainer is responsible for the personal data they input into the RIPE Database and for obtaining the relevant individual’s consent before doing so when required by law. If the maintainer does not respond, you may refer to the [RIPE NCC Procedure for the Removal of Personal Contact Details from the RIPE Database](https://apps.db.ripe.net/docs/removal-of-personal-data/ "External link to https://apps.db.ripe.net/docs/removal-of-personal-data/").

This procedure describes the terms under which the RIPE NCC may remove personal data from the RIPE Database upon the request of the data subject.

If you are subscribed to any RIPE mailing lists, you can unsubscribe yourself at any time or change your preferences by accessing this web page:

If you are subscribed to a RIPE NCC membership mailing list, you can unsubscribe by logging in to the LIR Portal of the member you represent and changing your details in the “Subscribed Mailing Lists” section.

If your name has been published on the RIPE NCC website as part of the attendee list for an event or meeting and you wish to be deleted from the list, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.ripe.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

If you have questions or concerns about the accuracy or appropriateness of any other personal information held by the RIPE NCC, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.ripe.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). RIPE NCC will respond and seek to correct any problems as soon as possible.

If you disagree with the RIPE NCC’s response or did not receive adequate support, you have the right to file a complaint with the [Dutch Data Protection Authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/ "External link to https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/")).

6\. Changes to this privacy statement
-------------------------------------

The RIPE NCC may change this privacy statement from time to time. The current version of the privacy statement will be available on www.ripe.net.

7\. Questions or suggestions
----------------------------

If you have any questions, suggestions or concerns about the issues discussed in this document, please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.ripe.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

On this page

-------------------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------------

----------------------------------------

----------------------------------------

--------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------

© 1992–2024 RIPE NCC

Your IP Address is: [51.195.149.220](https://apps.db.ripe.net/db-web-ui/query?searchtext=51.195.149.220)
